[Music]
Cheers Rai Rai Rai Hide
310 Three
Absent Aiko Noriyo
[Music]
Tasteful
Local
Three Brews
[Music]
Famous
[Music] Hello Mr.
Shinoda Hello Yes Welcome
Thank you
[Music] Well, there are
various kinds of sake, and there are basic sakes,
but what is in high demand right now is
sake called a special designation, and among those, there are two types: pure sake made from 100% rice, and sake with a small amount of added
alcohol added. Adding sake like the sake above is a
technique that was used in some parts of Japan during the Edo period, originally to improve preservation, and
then, based on that technique, when there was a
shortage of raw materials,
adding alcohol was temporarily done to increase the quantity even a little,
but now that there are
plenty of raw materials, the only ones that remain are those with a
small amount added. [Music] Adding sake  This helps
retain the aroma, and the clean
taste is what makes it so popular
even today. It also has advantages in terms of its
preservation and resistance to change, which was its original purpose.
[Music]
Preservation
One of its characteristics is that after it is bottled, it is
pressed and stored as is, so
even though it has been about six months since it was pressed, there are still
some bubbles in the glass, indicating that the carbon dioxide
gas has not evaporated. Because there is a lot of carbon
dioxide gas, there is
less oxygen, so it is less likely to change. Each
company nowadays has developed technology to slow down the changes so that it does not change very quickly. In
general, it is because it is so
clean, so
for example, when it is served with yakitori and sauce, if you
want to gently complement a strong, rich flavor, we
recommend pairing it with this sake. If
you want to add more umami to it, you can also
try a different order of sake.
Yamagata Prefecture, well, as for its characteristics, about
30 years ago, with the aim of making
Yamagata Prefecture a truly independent region of Japan, and to become
known as a famous place in Japan even on the world stage, they promoted an
overall improvement in level, such as
technical exchanges between Sakakura breweries, and the
guidance of teachers in the prefecture to quickly focus on what is called a high-grade brewery, or what is called a major
brewery.
Even now, Yamagata
Prefecture has data on the average pre-fermentation rate, but in terms of breweries, it is
not that many, ranking about 10th in Japan,
but in
terms of maba, it is the second
lowest after Yamaguchi Prefecture, and the proportion of sake produced on-site is
very high. Furthermore, Yamagata Prefecture is
characterized by very heavy snowfall and many mountains, and the snow that accumulates on the mountains
melts and settles in the ground, becoming abundant water.
Especially when there has been a lot of snow recently...  、  We
created something called Oginba Junma. Oginba was not
generally used until then, but as Oginba Junma
became more common,
Yamagata Prefecture
developed Yukimegami as the rice for Oginba. There are three types of rice that are representative of Yamagata Prefecture,
but
when we made the fourth, we crossbred it with Miyayama, which is a rice that doesn't dissolve very easily and has
the characteristic of making sake with a great texture and a
very clean taste. Based
on that, we decided to
create an original sake in Yamagata Prefecture, and with the
aim of creating a rice that can be used widely and in all kinds of ways, we developed a rice that
dissolves more easily than Miyayama and has a
good flavor, and that is Dewa. Based on Dewa, in
order to make a clean taste even in pure sake, we developed Dewa no Sato, which has a
low tapioca content and a very high heart rate when drinking sake, and
that is Dewa は、  We offer a variety of
flavors, from moderately dry to sweet and dry to very sweet. Also, we probably
use Junmai Ginba as the main ingredient, probably close to 40%,
so we are very
familiar with the brewing process. First of all, it is a
dry sake, and it is a very
distinctive product even among Japanese sakes. And
here is the Junmai Ginba Extra Dry.
Generally, Junmai Ginba has a rich aroma, and
this one also has a very rich aroma,
but while in such cases we usually make it slightly sweet to
match the image of the aroma,
this one is deliberately made dry. You
can feel the flavor when you first taste it, but the aftertaste is crisp, as is typical of a dry sake. It is
very popular with people who like to pair it with various kinds of sake and dishes, and it is
especially good with oily meat dishes and other
richly flavored foods.  It's been well-
received because its excellent qualities make food and drinks go down so well. The
rice itself is a very rare
variety with a low production volume. The
most produced variety in Japan is Yamada rice,
but this is the parent generation of Yamada
rice, and its characteristics include being easily changed and difficult to
cultivate, making it quite difficult to grow. This sake is made by
luxuriously polishing such precious rice. The
rice itself was originally highly regarded,
but because it was difficult to cultivate, it was crossbred with Yamada-shiki, a variety with a
shorter stem, to create Yamada-shiki, which is also a
history, so the
potential of the rice is very
high. This is the original Yamada rice,
but the
initial target was pure milk, but
our company has created a sake that is polished to
33%, as the name suggests, and is exclusively sold at our company.  It has a
moderate amount of umami, and I
think it's a very easy-to-drink, good sake.
Dry High School
2nd year
Just
[music]
[music] It's
normal I've
introduced this dry sake,
but this one is actually a sweet sake, and in terms of alcohol content it's a
very sweet 20.
As for how to make this sweet sake, normally, the
main alcohol is added at the very end, just before
pressing the mash, but to
make a sweet sake, the
main alcohol, which is usually added at the end, is
added at the very beginning of the mash, raising the
alcohol content in the mash earlier than usual,
suppressing the metabolism of the alcohol and leaving the
sweetness. I
think this is probably the only way to make a sweet sake like this in Japan.
[Music]
Kuchikuchi Ka
Special
Edition I am
happy that the number of people drinking this amazing sake overseas has increased significantly compared to before, and I would like to work hard to let more and
more
people know about this sake.
[Music]
Shinsei
Go [Music] [
Music]
So
[Music]